Rory Hartong-Redden

June 11, 2024 | Boulder, CO | roryhr@gmail.com | roryhr.com

Summary

Experienced data scientist and machine learning engineer with eight years of experience in analytics, data engineering, and machine learning. Proven ability to define and implement solutions for complex business problems, deploy machine learning models, and ensure high availability and durability of services.

Tools

Python, Git, Shell, Terraform, Elixir SQL, Metabase, Postgres, Spark, Hadoop, S3 Docker, AWS, CircleCI, Github CI/CD Jupyter Notebooks, PyCharm, ChatGPT **Python Tools:** scikit-learn, pandas, Flask, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn, pytest, Conda

Professional Experience

• SyBridge Technologies (Fast Radius)

Boulder, CO

Technical Manager and Lead Data Scientist

Aug 2021-May 2024

- Ensured high availability of revenue-critical APIs through high-quality code, comprehensive test suites, and synthetic Datadog tests in production
- Created SQL queries in Metabase to collect training data and track model performance over time
- Fast Radius Chicago, IL

 Data Scientist Feb 2020-Aug 2021
 - Tech stack: Python, scikit-learn, Flask, Docker, AWS ECS, Datadog, Metabase, SQL
 - Deployed a Dockerized machine learning model for our eCommerce contract manufacturing business, progressing from ad hoc statistical data exploration to production deployment, to instantly generate customer quotes for the FDM 3D printing process

• runtastic Linz, Austria
Data Engineer Oct 2018–Sep 2019

- Tech stack: Python, Spark, Hadoop, Flume, Oozie, Hive, RabbitMQ
- Led the design and deployment of a "People You Might Know" data product using Spark, scikitlearn, SparkML, and Elasticsearch
- Built a data exchange prototype with Apache Kafka and a production system with AWS S3

• Allstate Menlo Park, CA
Research Analyst Jul 2016-Sep 2018

- Tech stack: Python, pandas, TensorFlow, Spark, Julia, PostGIS
- Trained machine learning models and analyzed telematics and crash data for risk prediction
- Co-authored a paper on our research "Real-time Prediction of Intermediate-Horizon Automotive Collision" with the Stanford Intelligent Systems Lab

Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara

Santa Barbara, CA Dec 2014

MS Mechanical Engineering

- Tech stack: MATLAB, SolidWorks, IATEX
- Thesis research: Measured Faraday waves using a novel image processing technique for cheap 3D high-speed mm-resolution measurement over a surface area of $225\,\mathrm{cm}^2$
- University of California, Santa Barbara

Santa Barbara, CA June 2010

BS Physics & BS Mechanical Engineering